sociomantic.com 2014-04-25

# Privacy Policy English | Sociomantic Labs

**Sociomantic Labs**  takes the privacy and security of your data very seriously. We are an online advertising technology company that helps advertisers to deliver more relevant online display (banner) advertisements using anonymous, non-personally identifiable information.  We adhere to the online advertising industry’s _Framework for Online Behavioural Advertising._ You can read the framework and learn more about how this type of advertising works at the [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) website.

You can opt-out of seeing ads personalized by Sociomantic by selecting the checkbox below or on the [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) website.

When you opt-out, a new cookie is placed in your web browser that tells our technology to cease data collection from and ad delivery to your browser. You can opt-in to Sociomantic’s ads again at any time by un-checking the box above.

Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict your cookies via browser controls, or if you use another browser or another device, you will need to renew your opt-out decision. Furthermore, this opt-out only applies to ads delivered by Sociomantic, and does not opt you out of ads delivered by other companies.

Read more about cookie control in our Privacy Policy below.

## What Kind of Data is Collected by Sociomantic, and How is it Used?

We use browser cookies to collect anonymous, non-personally identifiable information (non-PII) about your interactions with the ads that we show and the websites of our clients (advertisers). The non-PII we collect is never attached to or combined with any personally identifiable information (PII), and is delivered anonymously and securely to our partners and clients for the purposes of delivering more relevant online advertising.

Read more about the data collected and stored and how it is used in our Privacy Policy below.

This policy is effective as of August 1, 2010.  
Last Updated: September 1, 2013

**Sociomantic Labs**  takes the privacy and security of your data very seriously. Sociomantic Labs (referred to as “Sociomantic,” “we,” “us,” “our”) is an online advertising technology company that helps advertisers to deliver more relevant online display (banner) advertisements using anonymous, non-personally identifiable information.

## Corporate Website Privacy Policy

This section of the privacy policy refers to your interactions with our homepage and all related domains and subdomains.

### Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”)

Sociomantic collects PII (such as your name, email address, or phone number) when you provide it to us directly, for example by using the contact form on our homepage, or when you contact us via email. We use this information to respond to your inquiry, request, or comment, and then we store the information for a reasonable time to complete correspondence and keep a record of communications. We will never share your PII with non-affiliate third parties unless obligated by the national law of the Federal Republic of Germany or international governance. If you would like to update or delete the PII we have on file for you, please feel free to contact us.

### Anonymous Data (non-PII)

Our website places small text files on your web browser called [cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "All about cookies"). Cookies are small text files placed on your computer used to store a record. Sociomantic uses cookies to store only non-personally identifiable information (non-PII). We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * Website customization: These first-party cookies remember your preferences on our website, such as language preference or your login credentials for our user interface.
  * Website analytics: These third-party cookies help us analyze our web traffic to improve the effectiveness of our website. They collect information such as your browser type, which pages were visited and for how long, and what country you are browsing from.
  * Online advertising: The Sociomantic Sonar cookies are used for online advertising. These cookies enable us to serve you more relevant advertisements as you surf the web. They collect information such as how you interact with our clients’ online shops or the online banners that we serve.
  * Social sharing and other third-party cookies: Some functionalities of our website include third-party tools that use cookies to help you share interesting information with others. For example, if you are signed into Facebook in your browser, you have the option to share certain articles from our site via Facebook because a cookie is used to remember your login credentials.

We may share some non-PII with third parties, for example in reporting to our clients how you have interacted with their advertisements or web shops. Read the Controlling the Use of Your Information section below to learn about how you can manage your cookie preferences via opt-out and browser controls.

## Online Advertising Privacy Policy

Sociomantic’s online advertising technology helps our clients to deliver more relevant online advertisements. This section of the privacy policy refers to your interactions with our online advertising technology. If you are interested in learning more about how these technologies work in general, we recommend starting at one of these sites:

  * IAB Europe’s [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ "Your Online Choices") site
  * IAB’s [Privacy Matters](http://www.iab.net/privacymatters "Privacy Matters") site (learn about online behavioral advertising)
  * Digital Advertising Alliance’s [AboutAds](http://www.aboutads.info/ "AboutAds") site

### Types of Anonymous Information (non-PII) Collected

Our online advertising technology collects and stores only non-PII data, which is accessed using cookies. These cookies are saved to your web browser to help us collect information such as the web pages visited by your browser, the advertisements clicked, the items viewed in an online shop or added to an online shopping basket, etc. We also collect information on the performance of the ads delivered, for example how many times an ad was shown to a particular browser, whether or not the ad was clicked, and if that click resulted in an online purchase.

### How the Information is Used

The information we collect is used to help make the ads you see more relevant to you. We do this by showing you ads based on your previous online actions and other dimensions we have assigned to your browser based on the non-PII we have collected. This helps to reduce the amount of “spam” advertisements you see as you browse the web, and it enables advertisers to connect to people who would be most interested in their offering.

### Storage and Retention of Data

Sociomantic Labs has taken reasonable measures to encrypt and keep secure all of the data we collect. This data is stored for a finite amount of time within the bounds of German law and in compliance with international standards.

## Controlling the Use of Your Information

###### Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

We will never share your PII with non-affiliate third parties without your consent. Non-PII collected by our advertising technologies may be shared with our clients and partners for the purposes of delivering targeted online advertisements or aggregated reporting. The provision of your personal data to government institutions is only possible within the framework of the national law of the Federal Republic of Germany or in compliance with international governance.

###### Children

Sociomantic never knowingly collects personal information about users under the age of 13 or from pages targeted to users of this age group. In the event that it is brought to our attention that personal information about a person under the age of 13 has been collected, we will take reasonable measures to remove this information from our system.

###### Sensitive Information

We never knowingly collect sensitive information such as financial account numbers, social security numbers, pharmaceutical prescriptions, or medical records.

###### Cookie Control

Most modern web browsers give users the option to control the placement of cookies and/or to delete cookies that have been acquired while browsing the web. You can access these options in the preferences or options section of your web browser.

## Links to Other Websites and Partner Cookies

Our website may include links to other websites and third parties which are not directly affiliated with Sociomantic and are therefore not covered by this privacy policy. While we strive to link to companies with reputable privacy practices, we cannot guarantee that their policies will match our own. Furthermore, the use of cookies by our partners or sites we have linked to is not covered by this privacy policy. Please check the privacy policies of the website(s) you visit when questions arise.

This privacy policy is subject to change. The date of changes to this policy will be posted at the top of this policy. When we make any material change to this privacy policy, we will post a notice on our homepage to alert visitors to the changes.

If you have any questions about our privacy policy or security practices, please contact us at our German headquarters.

sociomantic labs GmbH  
Paul-Lincke-Ufer 39/40  
10999 Berlin  
Germany
